Register of the Robert Daniel Murphy papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings I, 1937-1977
  - "Political Factors in War", National War College, Washington, D.C., Typescript, January 7, 1952 (Folder 2)
  - Remarks, American Club, Belgium, Typescript, press release, January 24, 1952 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks, Grandes Conferences Catholique, Charleroi, 2 typescript copies (1 in English, 1 in French), January 25, 1952 (Folder 4)
  - Remarks, Societe d'Economie Politique, Fondation Universitaire, Brussels, 2 typescript copies (1 in English, 1 in French), press release, January 29, 1952 (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, American Chamber of Commerce, Typescript, draft, February 5, 1952 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, American Club of Antwerp, Typescript, February 22, 1952 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, University of Liege, 2 typescript copies (1 in French, 1 in English), March 4, 1952 (Folder 8)
  - Transcript of telecast on Belgium, Carbon copy, April 6, 1952 (Folder 9)
  - Remarks on arrival in Japan, Carbon copy, April 21, 1952 (Folder 10)
  - "The Soldier and the Diplomat", Foreign Service Journal, Printed copy, May 1952 (Folder 11)
  - Remarks at the signing of the Tripartite Fisheries Convention, Printed copy, May 9, 1952 (Folder 12)
  - Remarks, American-Japan Society, Carbon copy, May 29, 1952 (Folder 13)
  - Remarks, Seiwa Kai Society of Tokyo, Typescript, June 10, 1952 (Folder 14)
  - Remarks, Tokyo Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Typescript, carbon copy, memorandum, press release, June 16, 1952 (Folder 15)
  - Remarks, American Chamber of Commerce, Tokyo, Typescript, press release, June 24, 1952 (Folder 16)
  - Remarks, Haneda, Typescript, carbon copy, July 1, 1952 (Folder 17)
  - Remarks, Ochanomizu University, Tokyo, Typescript, press release, July 11, 1952 (Folder 18)
  - Remarks, Black Ships Festival, Typescript, press release, July 15, 1952 (Folder 19)
  - Remarks, American-Japan Society of Kobe, Carbon copy, July 16, 1952 (Folder 20)
  - Remarks, Osaka, Press release, July 17, 1952 (Folder 21)
  - "Japan and Free Asia", American Japan Society, Carbon copy, September 1952 (Folder 22)
  - Remarks at the presentation of American law books to the Supreme Court of Japan, Press release, September 2, 1952 (Folder 23)
  - Remarks, United Nations Association of Japan, Typescript, press release, September 24, 1952 (Folder 24)
  - Remarks, Second World Conference of Buddhists, Tokyo, Press release, September 25, 1952 (Folder 25)
  - Remarks, Rotary Club of Tokyo, Press release, October 22, 1952 (Folder 26)
  - Research materials, 1953 (Folder 27)
  - Remarks on presentation of quota visa, Typescript, January 21, 1953 (Folder 28)
  - Remarks, American Club, Tokyo, Typescript, January 20, 1953 (Folder 29)
  - Remarks, National 4-H Club Congress, Tokyo, Press release, March 18, 1953 (Folder 30)
  - Remarks on presentation of Encyclopedia Americana to International Christian University, Press release, April 17, 1953 (Folder 31)
  - Remarks, American-Japan Society, Tokyo, Printed copy, April 24, 1953 (Folder 32)
  - Remarks, Chronoscope Program, Typescript, carbon copy, correspondence, August 21, 1953 (Folder 33)
  - Remarks, American Association for the United Nations, Draft, notes, September 13, 1953 (Folder 34)
  - Remarks, St. Matthew's Church, Typescript, memorandum, October 11, 1953 (Folder 35)
  - Remarks, John Carroll Society, Printed copy, correspondence, October 11, 1953 (Folder 36)
  - Remarks, New York Herald Tribune Forum, Printed copy, October 18, 1953 (Folder 37)
  - Remarks, Mayor's reception, Philadelphia, Carbon copy, October 23, 1953 (Folder 38)
  - "The Role of the United States", speech, World Affairs Council, Philadelphia, Printed copy, typescript, press release, October 23, 1953 (Folder 39)
  - Remarks, Navy League of the United States, Carbon copy, draft, correspondence, October 26, 1953 (Folder 40)
  - "The United States Looks at the United Nations", speech, Convention of the Texas Congress of Parents and Teachers, San Antonio, Press release, correspondence, November 19, 1953 (Folder 41)
  - Remarks, Oklahoma City Chamber of Commerce, Outline, correspondence, November 20, 1953 (Folder 42)
  - Remarks, Notre Dame New York President's Committee, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, December 9, 1953 (Folder 43)
  - Notes, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Research materials, 1954 (Folder 2-3)
  - Remarks, American Foreign Service Association, 2 printed copies in Foreign Service Journal, January 1954 (Folder 4)
  - WITHDRAWN. SECURITY CLASSIFIED MATERIAL (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, American Foreign Service luncheon, National Press Club, Typescript, carbon copy, news clipping, January 18, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, Harvard Law School Association, Draft, correspondence, January 20, 1954 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, Cardoza Foundation, Philadelphia, Typescript, carbon copy, draft, correspondence, January 26, 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Remarks, University Club of New York, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, January 30, 1954 (Folder 9)
  - "Brotherhood in the World of Today", speech, National Conference of Christians and Jews, New York, Carbon copy, press release, correspondence, February 4, 1954 (Folder 10)
  - Remarks, Marquette Alumni Reception, National Press Club, Washington, D.C., Typescript, carbon copy, February 24, 1954 (Folder 11)
  - Remarks, National Education Association, Notes, correspondence, March 7, 1954 (Folder 12)
  - "America, Japan and the Future of the Pacific", speech, World Affairs Council of Northern California and the American Legion, Typescript, carbon copies, press release, March 8, 1954 (Folder 13)
  - "Europe Is Important", speech, Town Hall Businessmen's Luncheon, Los Angeles, Typescript, carbon copy, press release, correspondence, March 9, 1954 (Folder 14)
  - "Some Problems of American World Relations", speech, World Affairs Council of Los Angeles, Typescript, carbon copy, correspondence, program, March 9, 1954 (Folder 15)
  - Remarks, Japan Society Dinner, New York, Typescript, carbon copy, press release, correspondence, March 18, 1954 (Folder 16)
  - Remarks, West Point Founder's Day dinner, New York, Carbon copy, memoranda, March 20, 1954 (Folder 17)
  - Remarks, American Society of Newspaper Editors, Washington, D.C., Typescript, carbon copy, correspondence, April 17, 1954 (Folder 18)
  - Remarks, Knights of Columbus Pan American Dinner, Washington, D.C., Typescript, April 29, 1954 (Folder 19)
  - Remarks, United Defense Fund, Typescript, correspondence, April 29, 1954 (Folder 20)
  - Remarks, Massachusetts Committee, Catholics, Protestants and Jews, Boston, Typescript, correspondence, memorandum, May 6, 1954 (Folder 21)
  - Remarks, Inter-American Bar Association of the Bar Association of the District of Columbia, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, May 18, 1954 (Folder 22)
  - WITHDRAWN. SECURITY CLASSIFIED MATERIAL (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Commencement address, Fordham University, New York, Correspondence, press release, program, June 9, 1954 (Folder 2)
  - "The United States and the Uncommitted World", speech, Zionist Organization of America, New York, 3 carbon copies, press release, correspondence, June 24, 1954 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks, annual convention of Air Force Association, Typescript, press release, correspondence. Typescript of remarks on accepting Association Medal for Secretary of State John Foster Dulles, August 20, 1954 (Folder 4)
  - WITHDRAWN. SECURITY CLASSIFIED MATERIAL (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, President's Committee on Employment of the Physically Handicapped, Typescript, 2 partial carbon copies, correspondence, August 26, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, American Association for the United Nations, Press release, September 13, 1954 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, United States Naval Academy, Annapolis, Maryland, Typescript, carbon copy, October 7, 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Remarks at the rededication of the Foreign Service Memorial Plaque, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, October 11, 1954 (Folder 9)
  - Remarks, Business Advisory Council, Hot Springs, Virginia, Typescript, carbon copy, correspondence, October 23, 1954 (Folder 10)
  - "The Defense of Asia", speech, National Foreign Trade Convention, Typescript, press relase, correspondence, November 16, 1954 (Folder 11)
  - Remarks, Armed Forces Staff College, Typescript, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, December 9, 1954 (Folder 12)
  - Notes, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Research materials, 1955 (Folder 2)
  - Remarks, testimonial luncheon for Matthew Woll, Typescript, carbon copy, memoranda, press release, correspondence, January 8, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks, Australian-American Society dinner in honor of Prime Minister Menzies, Typescript, carbon copy, memorandum, correspondence, March 7, 1955 (Folder 4)
  - Remarks, fourth International Trade Fair, Seattle, Washington, Typescript, press release, memorandum, correspondence, March 11, 1955 (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Studies, Oak Ridge, Tennessee, Typescript, memorandum, correspondence, April 10, 1955 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, "On Wisconsin" Award, Department of State Auditorium, Washington, D.C., Press release, correspondence, April 15, 1955 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, International Chamber of Commerce, Washington, D.C., Typescript, carbon copy, memorandum, April 20, 1955 (Folder 8)
  - "Collective Security in the Air Age", Annals of The American Academy of Political and Social Science, Printed copy, May 1955 (Folder 9)
  - Remarks, Chamber of Commerce of the United States, Washington, D.C., Typescript, press release, clipping, May 2, 1955 (Folder 10)
  - Remarks, Foreign Service Institute, Memorandum, May 2, 1955 (Folder 11)
  - "Our Policies in Asia", speech, Foreign Policy Association, Pittsburgh, Typescript, press release, memorandum, correspondence, clipping, May 5, 1955 (Folder 12)
  - Remarks, Rockford Chamber of Commerce, Rockford, Illinois, Typescript, carbon copy, memorandum, correspondence, May 24, 1955 (Folder 13)
  - Testimony before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on the Geneva Conventions for the Protection of War Victims, Carbon copy, draft, June 3, 1955 (Folder 14)
  - Remarks at the presentation of the Laetare Medal to Ambassador Jefferson Caffrey, Notre Dame University, Typescript, message from Secretary of State John Foster Dulles, memorandum, draft, June 5, 1955 (Folder 15)
  - Commencement address, Georgetown University, Typescript, printed copy, correspondence, carbon copy, June 6, 1955 (Folder 16)
  - "United States Diplomacy", commencement address, Marquette University, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 2 typescript copies, printed copy, 2 carbon copies, memorandum, correspondence, June 8, 1955 (Folder 17)
  - Remarks on television program, "Youth Wants to Know" with Konrad Adenauer, Carbon copy, June 14, 1955 (Folder 18)
  - Remarks, Indiana University Conference on Problems of American Foreign Policy, Bloomington, Typescript, carbon copy, press release, memoranda, June 25, 1955 (Folder 19)
  - Remarks, Washington-Rochambeau Celebration, Newport, Rhode Island, Typescript, carbon copy, printed copy, correspondence, memorandum, July 9, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Statement before the House Foreign Affairs Committee on NATO Status of Forces Treaty, Press release, memorandum, July 19, 1955 (Folder 2)
  - Statements for Voice of America. Pakistan International Industries Fair, Typescript. Salonika, Greece International Trade Fair, Typescript, September 2, 1955 September 4, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks, Canada-United States Conference, University of Rochester, Rochester, New York, Two carbon copies, press release, memorandum, program, correspondence, September 1, 1955 (Folder 4)
  - Remarks, National Sales Executives, Washington, D.C., Carbon copy, correspondence, September 8, 1955 (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, International College of Surgeons, Philadelphia, Typescript, press release, agenda, correspondence, September 15, 1955 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, European-American Discussion Group, Garmisch, Germany, Memoranda, correspondence, September 23, 1955 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, Chamber of Commerce, Danville, Illinois, 2 carbon copies, memorandum, correspondence, November 2, 1955 (Folder 8)
  - Remarks, Committee on Foreign Affairs, Cleveland, Ohio, Partial typescript, carbon copy, correspondence, memorandum, November 3, 1955 (Folder 9)
  - Remarks, Supreme Lodge of B'nai B'rith, Washington, D.C., Typescript, press release, memoranda, correspondence, November 7, 1955 (Folder 10)
  - "Africa and Asia in the World Community", speech, Catholic Association for International Peace, Washington, D.C., Typescript, press release, memorandum, correspondence, November 12, 1955 (Folder 11)
  - "The Principle of Self-Determination in International Relations", Department of State Bulletin, Printed copy, November 28, 1955 (Folder 12)
  - Testimony before the Senate Judiciary Committee Hearings on Trading with the Enemy, Press release, November 29, 1955 (Folder 13)
  - Remarks, Seton Hall University, South Orange, New Jersey, Carbon copy, press release, memorandum, December 8, 1955 (Folder 14)
  - Research materials, 1956 (Folder 15)
  - Remarks, Pennsylvania Bar Association, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, Typescript, press release, memorandum, correspondence, January 20, 1956 (Folder 16)
  - Remarks, Dartmouth Club of Washington, Typescript, carbon copy, correspondence, February 7, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - Remarks, Newman Club Convention, New York, 2 carbon copies, memorandum, correspondence, February 12, 1955 (Folder 18)
  - Remarks, Washington Conference of Mayors, Printed copy, notes, correspondence, February 16, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - "For a Better World", Department of State Bulletin, 2 printed copies, March 5, 1956 (Folder 20)
  - Remarks, George Washington Alumni Luncheon, Typescript, press release, correspondence, March 24, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Remarks, The Christophers, Correspondence, March 27, 1956 (Folder 2)
  - Remarks, Symposium on NATO, College of William and Mary and the Norfolk, Virginia Chamber of Commerce, Press release, memorandum, correspondence, April 2, 1956 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks, American Society of Newspaper Editors, Press release, April 19, 1956 (Folder 4)
  - Remarks, Manhattanville College, Typescript, May 1, 1956 (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, sixth annual World Affairs Forum, Foreign Policy Association of Pittsburgh, Typescript, press release, correspondence, clippings, May 2, 1956 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, citizenship ceremonies, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, May 8, 1956 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, Father's Club of the College of New Rochelle, New York, Carbon copy, memorandum, correspondence, May 13, 1956 (Folder 8)
  - Remarks, Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama, Typescript, correspondence, May 14, 1956 (Folder 9)
  - Remarks, United States Committee for the United Nations, Typescript, carbon copy, May 15, 1956 (Folder 10)
  - Remarks, University of Chicago Club, Washington, D.C., Carbon copy, correspondence, May 23, 1956 (Folder 11)
  - Statement before House Subcommittee on Government Operations, Press release, May 31, 1956 (Folder 12)
  - Remarks, Army War College, Carlisle Barracks, Pennsylvania, Typescript, memorandum, correspondence, June 6, 1956 (Folder 13)
  - Statement on the President's Special International Program, Mimeograph copy, June 14, 1956 (Folder 14)
  - WITHDRAWN. SECURITY CLASSIFIED MATERIAL (Folder 15)
  - "Soviet Developments and Their Meaning for U.S. Foreign Policy", statement before the House Foreign Affairs Committee, Typescript, carbon copy, October 11, 1956 (Folder 16)
  - Remarks, Institute of International Affairs, University of Washington, Typescript, press release, memoranda, correspondence, 2 carbon copies, October 24, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - "Berlin, Symbol of Free-World Determination", Department of State Bulletin, Printed copy, 2 carbon copies, clipping, correspondence, October 29, 1956 (Folder 18)
  - Remarks, United States Delegation to the 11th United Nations General Assembly, Typescript, November 9, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Remarks, American-Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, New York, Typescript, carbon copy, printed copy, memorandum, correspondence, November 29, 1956 (Folder 20)
  - Notes, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Research materials, 1957 (Folder 2)
  - Remarks, America-Italy Society dinner, Typescript, carbon copy, memoranda, correspondence, January 15, 1957 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks, Brussels Fair luncheon, Outline, correspondence, January 24, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Remarks as participant, Bilderberg Group Conference, Memoranda, correspondence, program, background information, February 15-17, 1957 (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, presentation of film Weltschmerz, Typescript, February 20, 1957 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, Diplomatic and Consular Officers, Retired (DACOR), Typescript, correspondence, February 21, 1957 (Folder 7)
  - Statement to the House Foreign Affairs Subcommittee on Europe, Typescript, carbon copy, memorandum, March 6, 1957 (Folder 8)
  - Remarks, The Citadel, Typescript, memorandum, correspondence, March 8-9, 1957 (Folder 9)
  - Statement on the President's Special International Program, House Appropriations Committee, Typescript, March 13, 1957 (Folder 10)
  - "The United States Looks at the Middle East", speech, Georgetown University, Typescript, press release, correspondence, March 14, 1957 (Folder 11)
  - Statement before the Subcommittee on the Armed Services, Senate Foreign Relations Committee, Typescript, carbon copy, draft, March 18, 1957 (Folder 12)
  - Statement on passport policy, Senate Foreign Relations Committee, Press release, correspondence, April 2, 1957 (Folder 13)
  - "Building for Peace", speech, tenth annual Conference on World Affairs, University of Colorado, Typescript, memorandum, correspondence, program, April 4, 1957 (Folder 14)
  - Remarks, Foreign Relations Commission of the American Legion, Typescript, carbon copy, April 25, 1957 (Folder 15)
  - Remarks, Catholic Women's Club, New Rochelle, New York, 2 carbon copies, memorandum, correspondence, April 28, 1957 (Folder 16)
  - Remarks, National Council of Catholic Men, Cincinnati, Ohio, Typescript, press release, program, background information, memorandum, correspondence, May 11, 1957 (Folder 17)
  - Commencement address, Catholic University of America, Washington, D.C., Typescript, press release, correspondence, June 9, 1957 (Folder 18)
  - Commencement address, University of Pittsburgh, Typescript, carbon copy, draft, correspondence, memoranda, clipping, June 12, 1957 (Folder 19)
  - Statement, House Armed Services Committee on H.R. 8704 (Exercise of Foreign Criminal Jurisdiction over Members of the Armed Forces Serving Overseas), 2 carbon copies, July 26, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - WITHDRAWN. SECURITY CLASSIFIED MATERIAL (Folder 2)
  - Remarks, annual Conference of U. S. Mayors, Typescript, press release, memorandum, correspondence, September 9, 1957 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks to the United States Delegation to the 12th United Nations General Assembly, Outline, September 13, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Remarks, 175th anniversary of the Great Seal, Typescript, September 16, 1957 (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, United Givers Fund Appeal, Typescript, September 23, 1957 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, American representatives of the World Veterans Federation, Outline, October 4, 1957 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, Mid-Career Class, Foreign Service Institute, Outline, October 4, 1957 (Folder 8)
  - Remarks, Business Advisory Council, Notes, outline, correspondence, memoranda, October 25-26, 1957 (Folder 9)
  - WITHDRAWN. SECURITY CLASSIFIED MATERIAL (Folder 10)
  - "Some Major Aspects of Current Foreign Policy", speech, Non-Governmental Organizations Conference on Foreign Policy, Typescript, carbon copy, December 9, 1957 (Folder 11)
  - Notes, 1958 (Folder 12)
  - Research materials, 1958 (Folder 13)
  - "Diplomats and Soldiers", Federalist, 2 printed copies, correspondence, draft, press release, Fall, 1958 (Folder 14)
  - Remarks, Veterans of Foreign Wars, Draft, February 3, 1958 (Folder 15)
  - Remarks, Council on Foreign Relations, Chicago, Memoranda, correspondence, February 21, 1958 (Folder 16)
  - Statement, Senate Committee on Foreign Relations on recent incidents in South America, Lebanon, and elsewhere, 3 typescript copies, May 19, 1958 (Folder 17)
  - Remarks, Department of State Auditorium, Typescript, May 22, 1958 (Folder 18)
  - Remarks, Colgate University Foreign Policy Conference, Typescript, press release, correspondence, memorandum, July 1, 1958 (Folder 19)
  - Remarks, St. Stanislaus Retreat League, Cleveland, Carbon copy, correspondence, memorandum, clipping, program, September 28, 1958 (Folder 20)
  - Remarks, Catholic Lawyers Guild, Press release, correspondence, clipping, October 1, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "Academic Training and Career Diplomacy", speech at the dedication of the Edmund A. Walsh Memorial Building, Symposium on Foreign Service, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., Typescript, carbon, press release, correspondence, October 13, 1958 (Folder 2)
  - Remarks, Business Advisory Council, Hot Springs, Virginia, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, memoranda, October 18, 1958 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks, Senior Foreign Service Officers Course, Foreign Service Institute, Outline, correspondence, October 21, 1958 (Folder 4)
  - Remarks, Chicago Advertising Council, 2 typescripts, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, memoranda, October 23, 1958 (Folder 5)
  - Remarks, Catholic Association for International Peace, Washington, D.C., Typescript, press release, correspondence, October 25, 1958 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, Milwaukee County war memorial, Typescript, press release, correspondence, memoranda, November 11, 1958 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, 45th National Foreign Trade Convention, New York, Typescript, carbon copy, press release, memoranda, correspondence, November 17, 1958 (Folder 8)
  - Remarks, A. and H. Kroeger Dinner Forum, New York, Typescript, 2 carbon copies, correspondence, memoranda, December 2, 1958 (Folder 9)
  - "The Strategy of Communist Advance", speech, Commonwealth Club, San Francisco, Typescript, 2 carbon copies, memoranda, correspondence, press release, December 12, 1958 (Folder 10)
  - Remarks, American Committee on Italian Immigration, Typescript, carbon copy, memoranda, correspondence, December 20, 1958 (Folder 11)
  - Remarks, World Affairs Council, Philadelphia, Press release, correspondence, memoranda, January 23, 1959 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - "American Foreign Policy Is Your Business", speech, Economic Club of Detroit, Typescript, press release, correspondence, clippings, memoranda, carbon copy, program, January 26, 1959 (Folder 2)
  - Remarks, Worcester Economic Club, Worcester, Massachusetts, 2 carbon copies, press release, memoranda, correspondence, February 10, 1959 (Folder 3)
  - Remarks, National Industrial Conference Board, Carbon copy, outline, correspondence, prospectus, memoranda, February 19, 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Remarks, Treasury Department Conference, Carbon copy, correspondence, memoranda, February 25, 1959 (Folder 5)
  - "The World Political Situation", speech, National War College, Washington, D.C., Typescript, correspondence, March 18, 1959 (Folder 6)
  - Remarks, Japan-America Society, Carbon copy, press release, correspondence, March 25, 1959 (Folder 7)
  - Remarks, Religion in American Life, Inc., Press release, memoranda, correspondence, April 13, 1959 (Folder 8)
  - Remarks, Notre Dame Club of Chicago, Press release, correspondence, memoranda, April 13, 1959 (Folder 9)
  - Remarks, Bellarmine College, Louisville, Kentucky, Carbon copy, press release, memoranda, correspondence, program, May 13, 1959 (Folder 10)
  - Remarks, World Refugee Year, Memoranda, May 22, 1959 (Folder 11)
  - "International Political Situation", Secretaries Conference, Typescript, photocopy, correspondence, June 26, 1959 (Folder 12)
  - Remarks, Boys Nation, Draft, July 21, 1959 (Folder 13)